RG 128:001, Ex Libris Club of the Connecticut State Library
Connecticut State Library
Ex Libris Club records
1912-1951
Connecticut State Library
Ex Libris Club (Hartford, Conn.)
3.5 cubic feet
Formed in 1912, the Ex Libris Club was a social organization of employees of the State Library and the Supreme Court. The Club held parties and picnics, sent cards and flowers, attended weddings and christenings, published an internal newsletter entitled the State Library Echo, and kept scrapbooks of members and activities. In 1951 employees disbanded the club and formed the State Library and Supreme Court Club, 1951-1986.
RG128_001
Multiple
Historical Note
Formed in 1912, the Ex Libris Club was a social organization of employees of the State Library and the Supreme Court. The Club held parties and picnics, sent cards and flowers, attended weddings and christenings, published an internal newsletter entitled the State Library Echo, and kept scrapbooks of members and activities. In 1951 employees disbanded the club and formed the State Library and Supreme Court Club, 1951-1986.
Scope and Content
Include the original charter and constitution, bylaws, minutes of meetings, reports, financial records, records of the Flower Committee, scrapbooks and miscellaneous publications, lists, and correspondence.
Related Material
RG 012, Connecticut State Library.
RG 128:002, State Library and Supreme Court Club.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Ex Libris Club (Hartford, Conn.)
Subjects:
Ex Libris Club (Hartford, Conn.) -- Records and correspondence
Document Types:
Bylaws (administrative records); Constitutions; Correspondence; Financial records; Scrapbooks; Reports; Minutes
Restrictions on Access
Some of these records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Accession: T001539, 1912-1951
  - Secretary's reports, 1912-1951; 4 volumes (Box 1)
    Includes Charter, Constitution, by-laws, minutes, reports, etc.
    - 1912-1919, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1919-1929, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1929-1937, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1938-1951, 1 volume (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's accounts, 1912-1951; 6 volumes (Box 1)
    - 1912-1917, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1917-1932, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1925-1926, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1932-1947, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1946-1951, 1 volume (Box 1)
  - Flower Committee records, 1931-1950; 1 volume (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous publications, lists and correspondence, 1 folder (Box 1)
  - State Library Echo editor's account book, 1925-1935; 1 volume (Box 1)
  - Scrapbooks, circa 1919; 2 volumes (Box 2-3)
    Contains photos and other miscellaneous clippings, programs, and letters.
- Accession: 2007-030, 1925-1935
  - Editor's Copy of State Library Echo, 2 volumes (Box 1)
    - 1925 April-1930 June, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1930 October-1935 June, 1 volume (Box 1)